<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christian König</title>
    <link>https://chrkoenig.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Christian König</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrkoenig.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Island Biogeography</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/island-biogeography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/island-biogeography/</guid>
      <description>Island Biogeography My PhD work focused on the fascinating topic of island biogeography. The reason why biologists love to study islands is their geographic isolation. Emerging as sterile rocks from the ocean floor, islands are populated over long time spans by only those species that manage to cross the open sea. For the few species that succeed, a completely new environment &amp;ndash; typically with fewer competitors or predators &amp;ndash; awaits, leading to spectacular evolutionary shifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web applications with R-Shiny</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/r-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/r-shiny/</guid>
      <description>Web applications with R-Shiny Shiny allows building interactive web applications from R while having access to all the tools that set the language apart, i.e. advanced data processing, modeling and visualization capabilities and thousands of user-contributed packages.
During my postdoc, I was part of the ODMAP project to promote better documentation and reporting of biodiversity models. ODMAP stands for Overview, Data, Model, Assessment and Prediction and provides a step-by-step protocol to ensure a reproducible modeling workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data Ecology</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/big-data-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/big-data-ecology/</guid>
      <description>Big Data Ecology Biodiversity science is transitioning into the age of Big Data, with massively expanding digital data collections and infrastructure. To keep pace with these developments, biodiversity researchers are increasingly adopting practices and tools from traditionally more technical fields such as informatics and data science. I developed and held this three-day workshop for the BioMove research training group in order to equip their graduate students with the skills necessary to make their work count in the age of big data ecology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biodiversity Databases</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/biodiversity-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/biodiversity-databases/</guid>
      <description>Biodiversity Databases I have led and contributed to the development of multiple biodiversity databases. During my PhD, I was one of two main developers behind GIFT, the Global Inventory of Floras and Traits database. GIFT provides information on the geographical distribution and biological characteristics (functional traits) of more than 300.000 plant species worldwide. Geographical regions in GIFT, which range from small protected areas to entire countries, are processed using geostatistical methods to extract a variety of additional features, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPS</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/post/2021-11-15-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/post/2021-11-15-vps/</guid>
      <description>Hoster Domain Logging in and SSH LEMP stack I chose docker + Ubuntu 20.04 pre-installed, so can use docker to install packages. What&amp;rsquo;s missing is docker compose:
sudo curl -L &amp;#34;https://github.com/docker/compose/releases/download/v2.1.1/docker-compose-$(uname -s)-$(uname -m)&amp;#34; -o /usr/local/bin/docker-compose sudo chmod +x /usr/local/bin/docker-compose </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProjectionPreview</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/post/2021-11-09-projectionpreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/post/2021-11-09-projectionpreview/</guid>
      <description>Bash code to write projections into .csv file.
proj -l | sed &amp;#34;s/ : /;/g&amp;#34; | tee ./projections.csv </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world!</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/post/2021-10-04-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/post/2021-10-04-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my personal homepage!
Going forward, I will write here about my path from being an academic researcher to becoming a data scientist. Expect content on machine learning, statistical programming and data visualization, but also occasional reflections about the state of our world and the beauty of this planet. Come and join my on this journey!
To learn more about me and my work, head over to the About and Project sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I’m a biodiversity data scientist and ecological modeler who seeks new challenges outside academia.
Professional experience Since 2021
Freelance Data Scientist
Dec 2021 - May 2022 (expected) &amp;ndash; Software Developer @ Karlsruhe Institute of Technology
Shiny application development | Data Integration
Apr 2019 - Jul 2021 &amp;ndash; Postdoctoral researcher @ Humboldt University and University of Potsdam
Bayesian hierarchical modeling | Shiny application development | Predictive ensemble modeling of species invasions | Workshop organization and presentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Hierarchical Models</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/bayesian-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/projects/bayesian-models/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Hierarchical Models Bayes&#39; theorem provides a powerful way to incorporate uncertainty into statistical modeling. Two key differences set the Bayesian approach apart from classical frequentist statistics. First, the parameters of a model are treated as random instead of fixed variables, i.e. they are drawn from a probability distribution. This has substantial advantages when estimating complex models because the uncertainty surrounding model parameters can be propagated throughout the model. Second, Bayesian approaches take into account prior information about the distribution of a parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.io/top/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.io/top/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Angaben gem. § 5 TMG:
Christian König
Nollendorfstr. 24
10777 Berlin
Kontakt:
Telefon: 015253474680
E-Mail: chr.koenig@outlook.com
Haftung für Inhalte
Alle Inhalte dieses Internetauftritts wurden mit größter Sorgfalt und nach bestem Gewissen erstellt. Für die Richtigkeit, Vollständigkeit und Aktualität der Inhalte können wir jedoch keine Gewähr übernehmen. Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
