<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tops on Christian König</title>
    <link>https://chrkoenig.github.io/top/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tops on Christian König</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://chrkoenig.github.io/top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a biodiversity data scientist and ecological modeler who seeks new challenges outside academia.
During my scientific career, I acquired in-depth knowledge in areas ranging from R programming, statistical modeling, database development to independent problem solving and effective communication. I successfully concluded projects as diverse as predicting the geographical origin of island species, making conceptual contributions to biodiversity data integration, and developing an interactive shiny web application to improve documentation of ecological models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://chrkoenig.github.io/top/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrkoenig.github.io/top/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Angaben gem. § 5 TMG:
Christian König
Nollendorfstr. 24
10777 Berlin
Kontakt:
Telefon: 015253474680
E-Mail: chr.koenig@outlook.com
Haftung für Inhalte
Alle Inhalte dieses Internetauftritts wurden mit größter Sorgfalt und nach bestem Gewissen erstellt. Für die Richtigkeit, Vollständigkeit und Aktualität der Inhalte können wir jedoch keine Gewähr übernehmen. Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
